Kingsley Ofosu

kingsleyofosu@yahoo.com

+ [233] 201-694-902 / 541-424-292

kingsleyofosu.com

https://linkedin.com/in/kingsleyofosu

https://github.com/kofosu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a results-driven full stack developer with several years of experience in applications development and a strong background in database administration.

I am an expert in devising tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries and a cyber security enthusiast.

I am flexible enough to work in a team, but also enjoy working independently. I also possess superb communication skills.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- C#
- VB.NET
- Node.js
- ASP.NET Core MVC
- SQL

- Angular
- Ionic
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Data Stores SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL and MongoDB
- Git

EXPERIENCE

Vodafone Ghana Accra, Ghana

Application Developer

March, 2020 – Present

- Develop RESTful API with Node.js and Express.js and write its documentation.
- Integrate user-facing elements developed by front-end developers with server-side logic.
- Model, design and maintain Oracle database.
- Setting up and maintaining backend server.

ThinkWell Solutions Limited

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana

Software Developer/Database Administrator

January, 2014 – Present

• Designing, coding, debugging, testing and maintaining of Web/Desktop Applications.

- Modelling, designing and maintaining database for applications.
- Ensuring all applications meet the Software Requirement Specifications.
- Monitoring website and platform performance.
- Managing hosting environment for websites and applications.
- Conducting training sessions for clients on the use of developed systems.

EDUCATION

Catholic University College of Ghana

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2009 – August, 2013

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Google Africa Developer Scholarship Program with Andela and Pluralsight

Mobile Web Specialist

May, 2019 – December, 2019

Pluralsight, Inc.

Used pluralsight.com, an online education platform, to take courses offered by subject-matter experts, to acquire knowledge and skills in web development and cyber security.

- Developed a familiarity, solidified and enhanced my skills in Python, JavaScript plus Node.js, Angular, HTML5 and CSS3.
- CompTIA Network+ courses Developed a familiarity with networking concepts, operations and procedures.
- CompTIA Security+ courses Developed a familiarity with how to install and configure systems to secure applications, networks and devices.